Feel the love.
Deadpool is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Tim Miller.
The origin story of former Special Forces operative turned mercenary Wade Wilson, who, after being subjected to a
rogue experiment that leaves him with accelerated healing powers, adopts the alter ego Deadpool.
Armed with his new abilities and a dark, twisted sense of humor,
Deadpool hunts down the man who nearly destroyed his life.
Wade Wilson / Deadpool, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Vanessa, played by Morena Baccarin.
Ajax, played by Ed Skrein.
Weasel, played by T.J. Miller.
Angel Dust, played by Gina Carano.
Blind Al, played by Leslie Uggams.
Deadpool is a 2016 American  superhero film based on the
Marvel Comics character Wade Wilson / Deadpool.
Directed by Tim Miller and written by Rhett Reese and Paul Wernick, it is a
spin-off of the X-Men film series and its overall eighth installment.
Ryan Reynolds stars as the titular character,
alongside Morena Baccarin, Ed Skrein, T.J.
Miller, Gina Carano, and Brianna Hildebrand.
In the film, Wilson hunts the man responsible for giving him mutant abilities and
a scarred physical appearance, becoming the antihero Deadpool.
Following a greenlight from 20th Century Fox in 2014 after test footage for a potential film was leaked,
principal photography took place in Vancouver, British Columbia, between March and May 2015.
Several vendors provided visual effects for the film, ranging from the addition
of blood and gore to the creation of the CGI character Colossus.
Deadpool premiered at the Le Grand Rex in Paris on February 8, 2016, and was released in the
United States on February 12, following an unconventional marketing campaign.
The film achieved both critical and commercial success, earning $782.6 million against a $58 million budget, becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of
2016 and breaking numerous records, including the highest-grossing film in the X-Men series and the highest-grossing R-rated film at the time.
Critics praised Reynolds' performance, the film's style, faithfulness to the comics,
and action sequences, though some criticized the plot as formulaic.
The film received many awards and nominations, including two
Critics' Choice awards and two Golden Globe nominations.
Two sequels have been released: Deadpool 2 (2018) and Deadpool & Wolverine (2024), with
the latter being part of Phase Five of the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
The film explores themes of superhero, anti hero,
mercenary, based on comic, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.